<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Researcher | Academician | Software Engineer on Amit Seal Ami</title>
    <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Researcher | Academician | Software Engineer on Amit Seal Ami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 01:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://amitsealami.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Qualification &amp; Experiences</title>
      <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/experiences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 01:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitsealami.github.io/experiences/</guid>
      <description>Academic Qualifications  M.Sc. in Software Engineering, Institute of Information Technology, University of Dhaka - 2014, CGPA 3.96 / 4.00,
M.Sc. thesis: An Efficient Approach for Providing Rationale of Method Change by Mining Software Repositories, Supervised by Dr. Md. Shariful Islam, Professor, Institute of Information Technology, University of Dhaka
 BSc. in IT (Major in Software Engineering), Institute of Information Technology, University of Dhaka - 2012, CGPA 3.93 / 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Publications</title>
      <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 01:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitsealami.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>2018  MobiCoMonkey - Context Testing of Android Apps; Amit Seal Ami, Md. Mehedi Hasan, Rayhanur Rahman, and Kazi Sakib; 5th IEE/ACM International Conference on Mobile Software Engineering and System (MobileSoft 2018), co-hosted with ICSE 2018, Gothenburg, Sweden++++++++++++++++++++++. A Proactive Self-Adaptive Framework for Context-Aware Mobile Applications; Md. Shafiuzzaman, Amit Seal Ami and Rayhanur Rahman; International Journal of Computer Applications 180(20):1-8, February 2018,  2017  MobileMonkey - A Contextual Stress Testing Framework for Android Application; Rayhanur Rahman, Amit Seal Ami, Kazi Sakib; International Journal of Computer Applications; Funded by Innovation Fund, ICT Division, Bangladesh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research &amp; Projects</title>
      <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 01:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitsealami.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Research/Funded Projects Mobile Application Testing Lab - ICT Innovation Fund 2015 The team members of this innovation fund project are Dr. Kazi Sakib, Md. Rayhanur Rahman and me, Amit Seal Ami. The target was to help make mobile application testing easier for both beginner and expert level mobile app developers. We targeted primarily Android app developers and created MobiCoMonkey, previously known as MobileMonkey. The project concluded satisfactorily in 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 01:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitsealami.github.io/news/</guid>
      <description>In construction!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitsealami.github.io/courses/</guid>
      <description>Courses I lectured on the following courses at Institute of Information Technology, University of Dhaka:
 CSE 401: Operating System (2015) CSE 501: Parallel Computing (2014) CSE 502: Web Technology (2014) SE 506: Design Patterns (2014) BUS 602: Management Information Systems (2016) SE 843: Software Metrics (2017, 18) MSSE 1044: Software Analytics (2017, 18) MSSE 1002: Formal Methods in Software Engineering (2016, 17, 18) PGD 202: Object Oriented Programming (2015) PGD 207: Mobile Application (2017) MITM413: Strategic Management (2016)  Responsibilities As part of academia, I have been assigned to different types of responsibilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associations</title>
      <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/associations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 01:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitsealami.github.io/associations/</guid>
      <description>I am frequently invited as Judge, Speaker and/or Mentor at various events due to my previous achievements as participants and contributions in similar events. Some of these are:
2018 Tech for Peace Initiative
2017  Seminar Speaker, Application Life Cycle Management (ALM), BASIS SoftExpo Mentor and Judge, Daffodil International University App Contest Speaker, International Women’s Day Celebration, Google Women Techmakers Bangladesh and Barisal University  2016  Mentor and Judge, National Hackathon Mentor, Smart City Hackathon Panel Speaker, Facebook’s F8 Meetup at Bangladesh Speaker, International Women’s Day Celebration - by IEEE AIUB Student Branch and Google Women Techmakers Bangladesh Judge, EATL-Prothom Alo App contest  2015  Moderator, IEEE Pro-Talk Technical Session on Mobile Apps Lifecycle and Ecosystem at EATL-Prothom Alo App Contest 2015 Bootcamp  2013  Youth Delegate, 100 Youth Delegate to India from Bangladesh  2009-2012  Event Contact and Organizer, Institute of Information Technology, University of Dhaka As the representative of the Director, Institute of Information Technology, University of Dhaka, I communicated with different public and private organizations regarding different types of event organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SE843: Software Metrics</title>
      <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/se843/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:01 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/se843/</guid>
      <description>Hello! This is the page for SE 843: Software Metrics offered at IIT, University of Dhaka. The contents are provided below:
 Introduction  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applied Data Science</title>
      <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/applied_datascience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 03:19:01 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/applied_datascience/</guid>
      <description>Hello! This is the page for Applied Data Science Course offered at IIT, University of Dhaka. The contents are provided below:
 Getting Started - Setting up the environment Tips and Tricks  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promotion</title>
      <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/ms1002/promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 03:19:57 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/ms1002/promotion/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schema Operators</title>
      <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/ms1002/schema-operators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 03:19:57 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/ms1002/schema-operators/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL 1</title>
      <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/mysql/mysql1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 12:18:57 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/mysql/mysql1/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal File Storage Android</title>
      <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/pgdit207/file/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 23:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/pgdit207/file/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activity Monitoring in Android</title>
      <link>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/pgdit207/activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 23:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitsealami.github.io/materials/pgdit207/activity/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>